{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Diplodocus","incorrectAnswers":["Triceratops","Velociraptor","Stegosaurus"],"question":"Which of these dinosaur s is known for its enormous size, with a long neck and tail?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Duckling","incorrectAnswers":["An Infant","A Colt","A Foal"],"question":"What would you call a baby mallard?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2008","incorrectAnswers":["2004","2006","2010"],"question":"In which year was WALL·E first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Sunflower State","incorrectAnswers":["The Prairie State","The Rusty State","The Wheat State"],"question":"What is the nickname for the state of Kansas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Land Rover","incorrectAnswers":["Fiat","Alfa Romeo","Citroën"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the Range Rover?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Oh what a day. What a lovely day!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"After all, tomorrow is another day!\"","\"Is it safe?\"","\"Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Mad Max: Fury Road'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Whoomp! (There It Is)","incorrectAnswers":["Electric Avenue","Barbie Girl","I Melt With You"],"question":"What song did Tag Team have a hit with in 1993?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Inflation","incorrectAnswers":["Deflation","Recession","Depression"],"question":"In 2008, what economic phenomenon caused prices in Zimbabwe to double every 24.7 hours?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"1984","incorrectAnswers":["Parade's End","The Age of Innocence","Howards End"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Big Brother'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Yanka Kupala","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Vladimir Nabokov","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Little Flute'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"What is this? A center for ants? How can we be expected to teach children to learn how to read…if they can’t even fit inside the building?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I’m the guy who does his job. You must be the other guy.\"","\"Of all the gin joints in all the towns in all the world, she walks into mine.\"","\"I drink your milkshake. I drink it up.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Zoolander'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"REM","incorrectAnswers":["Green Day","U2","Radiohead"],"question":"Who Had Hits With \"It's The End Of The World As We Know It\" & \"Orange Crush\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2001","incorrectAnswers":["1992","1995","1998"],"question":"In which year was Monsters, Inc. first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rage Against the Machine","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American band released the studio album 'Renegades'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gambia","incorrectAnswers":["Palau","South Korea","Oman"],"question":"Banjul is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pearl Jam","incorrectAnswers":["Anti-Flag","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Lightning Bolt'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Harvard","incorrectAnswers":["Stanford","Cornell","UCLA"],"question":"Founded in 1636, what is the oldest university in the USA? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nicholas II","incorrectAnswers":["Alexander III","Peter III","Ivan IV"],"question":"Who was crowned Tsar of Russia in 1896?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry I","incorrectAnswers":["George II","John","George IV"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1100-1135?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Janet Jackson","Christina Aguilera"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'Stronger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter and dancer released the song 'Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A touchdown","incorrectAnswers":["A field goal","An interception","A sack"],"question":"In the sport of American football, what is the term for scoring 6 points by carrying the ball into the opponent's end zone?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sherlock Holmes","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","The Lord of the Rings","Goosebumps"],"question":"In which book series does Professor Moriarty appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Yellow","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Nepal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"969","incorrectAnswers":["1","42","99"],"question":"According to the Bible, how many years did Methuselah live?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pope Benedict","incorrectAnswers":["Barack Obama","Queen Elizabeth","Nelson Mandela"],"question":"Who resigned from office in 2013?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"We’re goin’ streaking!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"No wire hangers, ever!\"","\"Listen to them. Children of the night. What music they make.\"","\"You've got to ask yourself one question: 'Do I feel lucky?' Well, do ya, punk?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Old School'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Americas","incorrectAnswers":["Southeast Asia","Africa","Europe"],"question":"From which part of the world do squashes originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Telegraph","incorrectAnswers":["Telephone","Fax Machine","Radio"],"question":"Which new communication technology was introduced in the 1830's and 1840's?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Europium ","incorrectAnswers":["Uranium","Eugelium","Iron"],"question":"Which Metallic Element Has The Symbol EU","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Duke of Wellington","incorrectAnswers":["The Earl of Marlborough","The Duke of Marlborough","The Earl of Wellington"],"question":"Who was the leader of the British forces during the Battle of Waterloo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denmark","incorrectAnswers":["Netherlands","Poland","Qatar"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Red with a white cross that extends to the edges.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Big Lebowski","incorrectAnswers":["Caddyshack","Broadcast News","Fast Times at Ridgemont High"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'The Dude'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Semaphore","incorrectAnswers":["Telegraph","Morse Code","Esperanto"],"question":"What is the name of a system of communication using flags, in which arm position is crucial in conveying meaning?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oakland","incorrectAnswers":["Washington, D.C.","Los Angeles","Philadelphia"],"question":"Which city lies on the east side of San Francisco Bay?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Myanmar","incorrectAnswers":["Timor-Leste","Chad","El Salvador"],"question":"Naypyidaw is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hungary","incorrectAnswers":["Slovenia","Israel","Moldova"],"question":"Budapest is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Exorcist","incorrectAnswers":["Up","Green Book","Sunset Blvd."],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'When a girl is possessed, her mother seeks the help of two priests to save her.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Luxembourg","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Louisa May Alcott","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Allan Poe","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Annotated Little Women'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Adventures of Tom Bombadil'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Latvia","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Sri Lanka","Senegal"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Carthage","incorrectAnswers":["Scythia","Parthia","Rome"],"question":"To which ancient civilization did Hannibal belong?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Frollo","incorrectAnswers":["Gaston","Hades","Jafar"],"question":"What is the name of the villain in the Disney film The Hunchback of Notre Dame?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Allan Poe","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Mario Puzo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Raven'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Small little pies","incorrectAnswers":["Little wheels","Large reeds","Bibs"],"question":"The pasta tortellini has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ricky Gervais","incorrectAnswers":["Steve Carell","John Oliver","Sacha Baron Cohen"],"question":"Who co-created the British TV show 'The Office' with Stephen Merchant?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Guy de Maupassant","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Anatole France","Albert Camus"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Bel Ami'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spey ","incorrectAnswers":["Tay","Tweed","Clyde"],"question":"Which Scottish river supplies over 90% of the water used in whiskey manufacturing?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Rommel","incorrectAnswers":["MacArthur","Montgomery","Zhukov"],"question":"Which WWII general was nicknamed 'The Desert Fox'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jimi Hendrix Experience","incorrectAnswers":["Poison","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which English-American psychedelic rock band released the album 'Electric Ladyland'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Niccolo Machiavelli","incorrectAnswers":["William Shakespeare","Voltaire","John Locke"],"question":"What was the name of the writer who wrote 'The Prince'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Beyonce","Adele","Shakira"],"question":"Which one-named singer showed off her acting in 'Ocean's 8' as a hacker/stoner named Nine Ball in 2018?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tony Stark","incorrectAnswers":["The Grandmaster","Alexander Pierce","Vision"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Robert Downey Jr.?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bosom Buddies","incorrectAnswers":["Pen Pals","Freaky Friends","Messy Mates"],"question":"Which eighties sitcom featured Tom Hanks in drag on a regular basis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Kra–Dai","Koreanic"],"question":"The language 'Taʽizzi-Adeni Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A bevy","incorrectAnswers":["A sedge","A gang","A pack"],"question":"What is the word for a group of quails?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["The Clash","The Rolling Stones","The Who"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Revolver'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Macbeth","incorrectAnswers":["Lady Macbeth","Macduff","Banquo"],"question":"Who killed King Duncan in Shakespeare's play 'Macbeth'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Gander","A Hen","A Soar"],"question":"What would you call a female rat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Santo Domingo","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Lisbon","Moroni"],"question":"What is the capital city of Dominican Republic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"San Francisco","incorrectAnswers":["New York City","Washington, D.C.","Los Angeles"],"question":"What city is associated with Alcatraz?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beastie Boys","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American hip hop band released the song 'Sabotage'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Nitrous Oxide","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium nitrate","Solid carbon dioxide","Calcium carbonate"],"question":"What chemical has the formula N2O?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Winnie the Pooh","incorrectAnswers":["In Our Time","Nine Stories","1984"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Eeyore'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bishkek","incorrectAnswers":["Thimphu","Tbilisi","Managua"],"question":"What is the capital city of Kyrgyzstan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Halley's Comet","incorrectAnswers":["Hale-Bopp","Shoemaker-Levy 9","Hyakutake"],"question":"Which comet causes the Orionids meteor shower each October?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Betty Friedan","incorrectAnswers":["Gloria Steinem","Margaret Atwood","Maya Angelou"],"question":"Who wrote the book \"Life So Far\", which includes how she wrote \"The Feminine Mystique\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Denzel Washington","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Sean Penn","Will Smith"],"question":"Who won the 2001 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Alonzo in Training Day?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bird","incorrectAnswers":["Fish","Dog","Tiger"],"question":"Which of these animals would you find on the Nestlé logo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Audrey Hepburn","incorrectAnswers":["Bette Davis","Catherine Deneuve","Selena Gomez"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including My Fair Lady and Breakfast at Tiffany's?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Seoul","incorrectAnswers":["Busan","Incheon","Daegu"],"question":"What is the capital city of South Korea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Incredible Shrinking Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Fly","The Thing","Invasion of the Body Snatchers"],"question":"A mysterious cloud of pesticide and radiation causes a disturbing reversal for Scott Carey in which classic 50s film?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"National Lampoon's Animal House","incorrectAnswers":["Jaws","Psycho","Scarface"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'John \"Bluto\" Blutarsky'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ticks and mites","incorrectAnswers":["The mouth and its diseases","Cosmetics","Schematic layouts"],"question":"What is Acarology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Saffron ","incorrectAnswers":["Turmeric","Cumin","Paprika"],"question":"Which spice is obtained from crocuses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Belgium","Switzerland"],"question":"In which country was Adolf Hitler born?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Starfish","incorrectAnswers":["Squid","Plankton","Lobster"],"question":"What type of animal is Spongebob's best friend Patrick?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tabasco ","incorrectAnswers":["Worcestershire","Habanero","Peri-Peri"],"question":"Which sauce is named after a river and state in Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Don't Give Up on Us","incorrectAnswers":["The Hustle","Macarena","Heart And Soul"],"question":"What song did David Soul have a hit with in 1993?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"USA","incorrectAnswers":["Saudi Arabia","Belgium","France"],"question":"In which country would you find Yosemite National Park?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cheetah","incorrectAnswers":["Lion","Leopard","Puma"],"question":"Which Member Of The Cat Family Cannot Retract Its Claws?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aaron","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo","Dylan","Zachary"],"question":"What Was Elvis Presley's Middle Name?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North Korea","incorrectAnswers":["Peru","Bolivia","Ghana"],"question":"Which of these countries has blue on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Papa","incorrectAnswers":["Pear","Peer","Peeler"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter P?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ulaanbaatar","incorrectAnswers":["Uliastai","Khovd","Ulaangom"],"question":"What is the capital of Mongolia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Solomon Islands","incorrectAnswers":["Serbia","Saudi Arabia","Spain"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sb' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Rosebud.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You shall not pass!\"","\"Why don't you come up sometime and see me?\"","\"Louis, I think this is the beginning of a beautiful friendship.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Citizen Kane'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Pig","incorrectAnswers":["A Horse","A Snake","A Swan"],"question":"What animal is Snowball in George Orwell's book Animal Farm?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Blue Ivy","incorrectAnswers":["Red Lily","Yellow Rose","Green Lotus"],"question":"What is the name of Beyoncé's daughter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Be Right Back","incorrectAnswers":["Beer, Ribs, Bread","Big Raunchy Bro","Being Really Bad"],"question":"What do people mean when type the letters 'BRB' in a message on the internet?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Big Bang","incorrectAnswers":["Eternal Inflation","Steady State","Oscillating Model"],"question":"What is the most widely accepted theory for the creation of the universe?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Die Hard","incorrectAnswers":["Robocop","Top Gun","Full Metal Jacket"],"question":"In which 80's movie did John McClane fight a group of terrorists in a skyscraper?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Five horizontal bands of red white blue white and red.","incorrectAnswers":["Three vertical bands of green white and red with a symbol in the middle.","Red field with a yellow sun in the center.","Red with a white crescent moon and star."],"question":"What does the flag of Thailand look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Maltese Falcon","incorrectAnswers":["The Thin Man","Blindness","One Hundred Years of Solitude"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Sam Spade'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jerusalem","incorrectAnswers":["Krakow","Moscow","Beijing"],"question":"Where is the wailing wall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The k in 'sock'","incorrectAnswers":["The m in 'mother'","The f in 'fish'","The n in 'no'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a plosive sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Seine ","incorrectAnswers":["The Rhone","The Danube","The Loire"],"question":"Which River Flows Through Paris?","difficulty":"medium"},